# Volodymyr Lysiuk

Email: volodymyr.lysiuk@gmail.com Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/vlysiuk

Phone: +38 097 941 91 22 Portfolio: <a href="https://vlyisuk.github.io">https://vlyisuk.github.io</a>

## Career objective

## Desired position: Delivery manager/Engineering manager/RnD director

I am all-in into managing complex issues and deliver the high-quality products. Being a software developer for more than 12 years, I have built the good engineering base and SDLC understanding. For the past 5 years I have been working as engineering manager, managing teams from 4 to 15 people. As a manager I enjoy empowering and inspiring people, building strong teams and culture within organization. I truly believe in leadership by example, and think that success comes with honesty, dedication and hard work.

## **Core competencies:**

- People management: performing 1 to 1 meetings and building PDPs, leading team process and direction, conflicts resolving
- Project management: building and controlling delivery plans, managing resources and cost, risk and change management
- Engineering: software developer for more than 12 years, building complex, high-load solutions, maintaining CI/CD and automation process
- Leadership: building team environment and culture, embracing and influencing company values, leading organizational initiatives and process improvements
- Certified Agile practitioner and Scrum Master

## Professional experience

#### **December 2019 - Present**

Position: Delivery Unit Team Lead at Playtika

**Description:** My main responsibilities include projects delivery from planning to deploying to production, leading and mentoring cross-functional development team, building the proper development process and product quality,

communication with stakeholders

### **July 2019 - December 2019**

Position: Development Team Lead at Global Logic

**Description:** Working for German company Zeiss. My main responsibility is to scale existing team and build the proper development process for better team

performance and predictability for business. I am responsible for building communication between distributed teams and aligning the understanding of the project scope and client priorities

#### November 2016 – July 2019

Position: Scrum Master/Team Lead

**Description:** Working for Swedish company Betsson. My responsibility is to grow motivated and high-performed professionals and support them on getting to the established goals. I am also responsible for projects delivery, technical excellence, communication with product owners and architect

#### **November 2014 – July 2019**

Position: Senior software developer at Ciklum

**Description:** Working for Swedish company Betsson. Developing payment system for Betsson Group services. Implementing and maintaining applications and services that require high availability and performance, working on distributed and multi-tier systems

**Technical stack:** .NET, C#, .NET Core, WCF, MS SQL, Javascript, NServiceBus, Rabbit MQ, Kafka, ASP.NET MVC, LINQ, EntityFramework, NUnit, Specflow, TeamCity, Jira, Git, Docker, Kubernetes

### September 2010 - November 2014

Position: Senior software developer at Ciklum

**Description:** Working for Swedish company Tobii (<a href="http://www.tobii.com/">http://www.tobii.com/</a>)
Developing software for analyzing and processing eye tracking and gaze interaction data. Designing and implementing products for disabled people to help them to communicate with others

**Technical stack:** .NET, C#, WPF, LINQ, XML, C++, COM, SQLite, EntityFramework, NUnit, Specflow, Moq, TeamCity, Jenkins, Jira, Git, Perforce

## April 2008 – September 2010

Position: Senior software developer at Tikle (<a href="http://www.tikle.com/">http://www.tikle.com/</a>)

**Description:** Developing value-added services and content management systems for one of the biggest Ukrainian mobile operator Life. Designing and implementing operator core services related to subscriptions, campaigns and users data. Holding technical meetings with partners

**Technical stack:** .NET, C#, ASP.NET, WinForms, MS SQL, ADO.NET, XML, CSS, HTML, SOAP, USSD, SMPP, WAP, SVN

## September 2006 – April 2008

Position: Software developer at Tikle

**Description:** Developing value-added services and content management systems

for one of the biggest Ukrainian mobile operator Life

Technical stack: .NET, C#, ASP.NET, WinForms, MS SQL, ADO.NET, XML, CSS,

HTML, SOAP, USSD, SMPP, WAP, SVN

#### April 2006 - September 2006

Position: C++ developer at Kvant

Description: Developing modules for a spatial monitoring system. Implementing

algorithms for objects definition and correlation

Technical stack: C++, MFC

#### September 2004 – April 2006

**Position:** System administrator, Laboratory assistant at NTUU «KPI» Department

of applied mathematic

**Description:** Installing and configuring software and hardware. Managing and supporting the local network. Managing users rights and access within the local

domain

## **Education**

**2003-2009** NTUU "Kiev Polytechnical Institute"

Department of applied mathematics Faculty of specialized computer system

Master degree

## Training Programs

## **April 2017 - May 2017**

Name: Target Course for middle management

Description: How to manage and lead teams, motivation, customer collaboration

Provider: Vera Shatskaya

### **July 2017**

Name: Time management

**Description**: Time management best practices

Provider: Vera Shatskaya

#### October 2018 - December 2018

Name: Target course for Business Leaders

**Description:** Introduction to finance, marketing, project management, customer

collaboration, team leading, risk management

Provider: Ciklum PM Education, Lviv Business School

## January 2019 - February 2019

Name: Effective communication

Description: Cultural differences, empathy, active listening, influencing,

negotiations

Provider: Nataliya Ostashko

#### March 2019

Name: Sales for IT

Description: Leads generation, marketing, customer engagement

**Provider:** Lviv Business School

## **Languages**

Ukrainian, Russian – native English – fluent

# **Certificates**

Certified scrum master PMI Agile Certified Practitioner